Diwali Puja. Los Angeles (USA), 9 November 2003
Diwali Puja. Los Angeles (USA), 9 Kasım 2003.
Today is the great day of Diwali.
Bugün büyük Diwali günü.
That means today is the great day .....(?)
Bunun anlamı, bugünün .........?
to make a greater light
dünyanın daha iyi bir yöne doğru gitmesi için;
for the world to move in a proper direction.
çok daha büyük bir ışık oluşturmak demektir.
It's a day of great joy, and those who join in this,
Bugün büyük bir neşenin günü ve buna katılan herkes de
are spreading also great joy.
bu büyük neşeyi yayıyor.
But the problems are there, as they say,
Problemler hala oradalar, fakat dedikleri gibi,
but for us there is no problem because there is no darkness,
bizler için problem yok, çünkü karanlık yok,
we don't see any darkness anywhere,
bizler hiç karanlık görmüyoruz,
we see lights, and lights, and lights.
bizler ışıkları ve ışıkları ve ışıkları görüyoruz.
Then what is the thing missing, missing is our sincerity.
O zaman eksik olan nedir?
We have to be very sincere with ourselves,
Kendimize karşı dürüst olmalıyız,
because it is not just a borrowed love or a borrowed joy,
çünkü bu ödünç alınmış bir sevgi değil
but it is from within the source,
O kaynağın içinden geliyor,
it's flowing, flowing and flowing.
akıyor, akıyor ve akıyor.
So that is to be awakened, and that love should flow,
Uyandırılması gereken işte bu, bu sevgi sürekli akmalı
and our small petty things like jealousies
ve kıskançlık, rekabet gibi
and competitions and all those things which spoilus
bize zarar veren ufak tefek önemsiz şeyler
must be washed away.
akıp gitmeli.
And it can be washed if your heart is full of love.
Eğer kalbiniz sevgi ile dolu olursa, bu yıkanabilir.
Today is a day of spreading love, light of love,
Bugün sevgiyi yayma günü, sevginin ışığını,
so that everybody feels enlightened and happy
bu sayede herkes aydınlanmış ve mutlu hisseder
and forgets these petty problems.
ve bu ufak tefek problemleri unutur.
I am happy that you have been able to get some hall,
Bir salon bulabildiğiniz için mutluyum,
it's all luck that we got it,
sahip olduğumuz şey tamamen şans,
people were so much worried about getting a hall.
herkes salon bulma konusunda çok fazla endişeleniyordu.
But it has just happened,
Ama sadece oldu işte,
so you should know also that our destiny is all also
bu yüzden bilmelisiniz ki, kaderimiz de
guided and looked after.
bu şekilde bakılıp, gözetiliyor.
You are already blessed people,
Sizler kutsama almış kişilersiniz,
there is no doubt about it.
buna şüphe yok.
And we should not worry about small things and small matters.
Küçük şeyler ve küçük meseleler hakkında endişe duymamalıyız.
It will all work out very well, you will see,
Her şey çok iyi gidecek, göreceksiniz.
if you just leave it to your destiny, which is very high,
Eğer her şeyi sadece çok yüksek ve çok büyük olan kaderinize
very great - in this your own destiny you will go very far.
bıraktığınız zaman, -bu kaderinizle çok ileri gideceksiniz.
This is the promise of Diwali
İşte bu hepinize Diwali'nin verdiği sözdür,
to you all, that you will reach highest
Sizler en yüksek ve en asil
and the noblest way of life.
yaşam şekline erişeceksiniz.
Every word I say will be there
Söylediğim her söz, söylediğim her şeyin öyle
to prove what I say is there.
olduğunu kanıtlamak üzere orada olacaktır.
Whatever petty problems you have,
Sahip olduğunuz her ne  tür gündelik sıkıntınız varsa,
they'll all be washed off.
akıp gidecekler.
All these are the messages from the Divine,
Bunların hepsi Tanrıdan mesajlar.
you don't have to worry about petty things,
Önemsiz şeylerle ilgili endişe etmenize gerek yok.
about money, about jobs, that's not your job.
Para gibi, iş gibi... Sizin işiniz bu değil.
Your destiny will work it out.
Kaderiniz bununla ilgilenecek.
You have a promise that you'll be looked after.
Gözetileceğinize dair size verilmiş bir sözüm var.
I hope you believe in that promise
Umarım bu söze inanırsınız
and are joyous in the highest way.
ve o en yüksek yolda neşe dolu olursunuz.
I bless you all from my heart, all of you,
Hepinizi, hepinizi, çok mutlu ve
for a very happy and prosperous Diwali.
refah dolu bir Diwali için kalbimden kutsuyorum.
Thank you very much.
Çok teşekkür ederim.